We've got a few more signings to dive
into.
>> This confus continues to evolve as the
season goes on.
>> Welcome in to Buccaneers Insider
presented by Hard Rock Bet Sports Book.
Casey Phillips here with Scott Smith and
Brie Dixs. Now Bri and I did a show last
week covering the majority of the free
agent signings, but
>> wish I would have been here.
>> I know we we missed you. We missed you
for the the free agent frenzy.
>> Yeah, not a good week to be away.
>> No, it it was not. Uh but you know what?
we covered it, but there were still some
signings that happened after that show,
plus some actual media availability from
some of the guys that we signed that we
hadn't gotten to hear from. So, we
wanted to make sure that we covered
that. First, uh, we wanted to let you
participate in the free agent franchise.
So, tell me about a couple of these
signings.
>> I watched your show and was very
jealous, but there were a few signings
the next week or resignings actually of
Titan KEF and guard Danfeny. And uh
those maybe don't make as big of a
splash as Alex Analone or Kadin
Muhammad, but
>> they're kind of sneakily important. The
funny thing about Kokee is
>> I think he had I don't think he had a
catch last year.
>> Mhm.
>> Or maybe one.
>> I don't think a single.
>> And yet as when he was placed on IR
after I think week two or three,
>> it so many guys went to the podium were
saying how important this guy is to the
offense and you're like what? I didn't
even tone, right? He's apparently a big
time tone setter. Plus, he's such a
great blocker and they move him all
around the formation and he's a great
special teamer and he's just a guy that
everybody in this building loves. So,
it's so good that he's back, right? And
then Dan Feny ended up starting like 10
games even though the Bucks signed him
off the Bills practice squad in
September. So, he wasn't even in the
team's plans when the season started,
but with all the injuries, he ended up
starting a lot of games. Now, the Bucks
do anticipate having uh their full
offensive line from 2024, all five
stars, which was a great offensive line.
They did awesome. And that means Cody
Malc and Ben Bredesen at the two guard
spots. But it's very, very important, as
we saw last year, to have reliable
veteran depth. So, I think those are two
very good ressignings by the Buccaneers.
>> Yeah, I would agree with that. And I
think again with the special teams
struggles last year, there are elements
like that that maybe go unnoticed of how
big of a role someone like him plays
that one player can make a pretty big
difference on special teams when
especially they're a specialist.
>> I think they're betting on that with the
signing of Miles Kellib.
>> I would agree with that. That one is
very exciting. Um all right. And so then
also Bri, I know we got a chance to hear
from Muhammad and his presser. So tell
me what you learned from that. One of
the things I really liked was him
talking about when asked what worked
well last year for his 11 sack campaign.
Didn't start a single game, but that
kind of production. And I really like
that he just said he got into a rhythm,
worked a lot on the pass rush, but also
just as you continue to build that
success, he said you become a lot more
confident, but also he said, I
complimented Aiden Hutchinson. we work
together, but also that competitive
mentality of wanting to get after the
quarterback to to be the best in number
wise kind of led to his success and also
just the excitement that he has now in
coming to Tampa Bay and working with
Vivea and Yaya Diab and trying to be the
numbers and get the stats.
>> Yeah, I think he's an interesting
signing for sure, but definitely
addresses some some needs on this team.
We know Jason loves to do it both in
free agency and the draft. I've seen
comparisons to the Shaq Barrett signing
in that um Mohamd was playing about I
think he played like 49% of the snaps
last year in Detroit. So 11 sacks is a
pretty nice total. I mean that's
actually more than Shaq ever had in any
season with the Broncos. But in both
cases the guys come in here with an
opportunity to maybe see his play count
rise
>> and see what if his production rises as
well.
>> Yeah, I agree. And you know, I wanted to
talk a little bit about Aan Robinson
because we'd mentioned last week that we
signed him, but his press conference
hadn't happened yet as of when we
recorded. And his press conference was
quite fun. Um, I think that we got a
window into the type of player. First of
all, we knew Coach BS had said that he
wanted the defense to get bigger.
>> Check.
>> Check. Um, large man.
>> Yes.
>> And to me, I feel like what I think
about when I watch him, I look at how
he's built. I look at the way he plays
and then I listen to him in his press
conference and I'm like are we getting a
Sue
>> Vita
>> tandem again that worked so well in the
Super Bowl and I feel like this to me
has the makings of that of course and
Domkakin Sue like had already had a very
long storied career at that point. So
I'm not necessarily saying that he's at
that level yet but I felt like the type
of the body type the style of play we
saw how much that elevated both of them
getting to play next to each other. Do
we have a chance to see something like
that? And I thought just in case people
hadn't seen it, not only is he large,
uh, he is large and in charge on the
field and his attitude and his approach,
um, you know, he and he talked about how
much he's excited to play next to Vita
cuz as he said, he wants to let the big
dog eat, which I enjoyed. Uh, and he
also said he's aging like fine wine. I
love that. Older he's gotten, the better
he's gotten, he said. But now I want
everyone to hear a little bit about his
mindset on the field and where he says
that that came from. comes from a little
kid that used to they used to try to
pick on for not having anything, for
being so poor. So, you know what I did
every day? Whoop somebody ass. Every
day. Every day you said something, I'll
beat you out of you. So, that's where
that came from. Even in college, you
joke around, I'm going I'm going beat
your ass. So, that's just how I became.
And I played the same way on the field.
So then I was like, you know, like
people talk and try to do like dirty
stuff and I just got tired of it. So I
just started letting people have it, you
know, let them know that I'm going to
beat what I'm going to do, how I'm going
to do it. And I'm sorry for cussing, but
that's just
>> how I am.
>> Please continue.
>> And um I just destroy like that's all it
was as a kid like how much
I guess if I can see mad like madness I
can create. So that's how I always saw
it.
I'm here for it. I'm here for it. I I
pity the offensive lineman on the other
side uh from him. And I also like that
he talked about, you know, his attitude
being contagious to the other guys out
there. That's why when you talk about a
tone setter, it's not just that that
person has the tone, it's that then it
becomes contagious to other people as
well. And I think that that little that
little bit of nastiness is going to is
going to help up front. That's what you
want.
>> Yeah. The Bucks wanted more size and I
think they wanted more of that, too.
Kind of like the Ryan Jensen effect.
>> Yes. I like that very much. Um All
right. So now I know also uh Jason Light
made a few comments about free agency
overall. So Bri, what were a couple of
things that he talked about that stood
out to you?
>> Well, I think one of the biggest things
for me was so our scouting department
places a lot of stress on getting
players that have really high character
off the field, but I liked that Jason
Light talked a lot about
specifically this year in free agency,
they wanted to get guys that were both a
blend of they have the character off the
field, but also they are nasty and edgy
on the field. So getting guys like
Analone and Robinson and Muhammad that
fit that blend in bringing that
intensity up. But I also like that he
said that with Yaya Diab think we've
seen really what he's capable of doing
because he said in terms of numbers you
look at the pressures when all of those
he ranks up in the be with the best of
the guys in the league. And just for
context so Yaya Dyabi in 2024 and 2025
had 125 pressures. He had a 15.9%
quarterback pressure rate in 2025. And
then among players with 300 plus pass
rush snaps, Yaya Dyabi finished eighth
in pass rush win percentage in 2024 and
2025.
>> But also the excitement of David Walker
who essentially had a red shirt year
last year. we never got to see him on
the field during the regular season and
that said he's kind of a freak and not
only did he was he ahead of schedule but
not only just with his athleticism but
just his genetic makeup and that our
trainers were really impressed with how
quickly he got up to speed.
>> Yeah, I think that's really interesting.
Scott, what about you? What were some of
the things that Jason talked about?
>> There was a lot about Mike Evans, of
course.
>> What shocking didn't see that coming.
>> There's a lot to unpack there. Um
beginning with the fact that the Bucks
didn't want Mike Evans to leave. Um,
there was an offer made monetarily that
was good, you know, that was better than
what he took and there could have been
more. Um, but Mike earned the right, as
has been said several times with Jason
Light, to to decide the next chapter of
his career, and it became clear at some
point that that's what he wanted. He
wanted a different chapter, a new
challenge. And so, everybody wishes Mike
well and says,
>> "Yes, he's the best offensive player in
franchise history, and that's not going
to change." and we're going to celebrate
him when his career is over uh for what
he did for the Buccaneers. Um but as
Jason said, you accept it and you have
to move on. And the good thing as as he
said, he talked to Mike a lot, of course
he always did. And that was his first
draft pick. They had a very great
relationship. And um
>> you know, Mike told him, I'm leaving
this team with a great receiving room.
Mike even feels that way. And so that's
the thing to look at. You have to move
on now. Now, if you I asked Jason, if
you were taking over this team and you
were presented with this receiver group
and you did not know that it used to
have Mike Evans,
>> how would you feel about it? And he's
like, "A lot of teams would kill, and
I'm paraphrasing there, but would would
be envious of this receiving group with
a Mecha Ibuka, Chris Godwin,
Jayla McMillan, who he thinks is going
to have another big step forward this
next year, and TZ Johnson, some other
guys that, you know, if you look around
the league, there's a lot of teams that
would love this receiver group." And
they are. And with Mike Leeing,
unfortunately, there are going to be
more passes for all these guys. There's
going to be more targets for all of
these guys and it's going to be exciting
to see what some of especially a guy
like Jaylen McMill or Iuka who at the
beginning of last year when everybody
was hurt
>> had to step up and be the number one and
was fantastic was one of the league's
best most productive receivers for the
first six or seven weeks. So nobody
wanted to see Mike go but the Bucks are
still pretty good pretty well set at
wide receiver.
>> I would agree with that. And then, you
know, we thought it'd be interesting to
talk about free agency moves by the NFC
South overall to kind of know how did
free agency not only affect us, but some
of the teams that we know we'll be
facing multiple times this year. Uh, so
let's start for you, Scott. What was a
team and signing that stood out to you?
>> Yeah, I think probably the most
interesting one amongst all the teams is
Tua Tonga after he was released by Miami
signing with the Atlanta Falcons. I've
seen some mixed analysis on that. Some
people don't think it was a great
signing. To me, you get him for you get
him for the minimum league minimum. You
don't know for sure if Michael Pennix is
ready to go for the start of next
season. And honestly, there was some
questions about if he's the answer. Uh I
personally think he probably is the
long-term answer for Atlanta. But in in
the meantime, you have Tungavo who as
recently as 2023 had 4,600 passing yards
and 29 touchdowns. I mean, it's not like
he's not talented,
>> right? And you know, interestingly, I
don't know how big of a fra factor this
was, but he's left-handed and so is
Pennix, so you don't have to adjust from
one to the other. That's interesting.
Um, I just think considering the fact
that you get him at a league minimum. I
think it was a great pickup by the
Falcons. I know not every analyst
agrees, but I do.
>> Yeah. And I'm sure for them they have
seen how important it is to have a
backup that knows what they're doing as
well. Depending on who wins that job,
what that looks like and uh to have two
different quarterbacks on your roster
that have had a lot of meaningful snaps
and both you have confidence in is uh
it's a very interesting move. Um you
know, I wanted to talk a little bit
about Carolina. They I know that they
sent us Aan Robinson, so you're kind of
wondering what is that going to mean for
for their defense. Um they signed a
couple people that I think it's safe to
say their defense got better.
>> Oh, for sure.
>> That they had one of the better Fian
signings when it especially comes to the
defensive side of things. So
>> Jaylen Phillips and Deon Lloyd truly two
of the top people available at their
positions. Absolutely.
>> Um and their biggest needs were pass
rush and kind of second level especially
pass coverage. Those were a couple of
their biggest needs. And I know that
Jaylen Phillips only had five sacks last
year, but he finished top 10 in
pressures, fifth in hurries. Um, you
know, he he does have some injury
history that last year was the first
year in three years that he'd been able
to play a full season. He's partially
torn in ACL. He's torn in Achilles. So,
it's a fair amount of guaranteed money
for a guy that's had some injury issues,
but if he's able to stay healthy, that's
a heck of a signing, a heck of an
addition to their defense. And then of
course Devin Lloyd coming off a Pro Bowl
season. He can cover tight ends and
running backs, great coverage skills,
also has the ability to get
interceptions. He had five interceptions
last year which would of course have led
our team and a lot of teams and had nine
in four years with the Jags at that
position. So, I mean, you know, Phillips
is going to also, I think, help Derek
Brown, who we know is an incredible
interior pressure guy that having the
two of them working off each other, if
either Derrick Brown's getting up the
interior, flushing him out, if Phillips
is holding the edge, that gives Derrick
Brown more of an opportunity. You pair
Lloyd with JC Horn back there, that
there's some pretty elite playmakers at
every level of their defense now. So, I
think they they definitely got better. I
I unfortunately really liked what
Carolina did in front
>> and it helps when you have the cap space
and are willing to spend the money. So,
but in addition to the two you talked
about, they came in a few days later and
got Rasheed Walker the tackle from uh
the Packers for one year and $10
million. I thought that guy was going to
get like a fouryear $100 million deal. I
don't know how they did that because
good left tackles on the free agent
market are rare. Yeah. and he he was
good for the Packers and they had their
left tackle um I don't know if I ever
pronounced his name right but echo Auanu
>> he got hurt in the playoff game and so
they're not sure they're he's almost
certainly not ready for the beginning of
the season he might miss a good balance
of the season he's still their guy for
the future but they got Walker on a
one-year deal to fill in if he needs to
play the whole season I that move late
in the first week of free agency just
floored me I was like they already got
these other two guys on defense and now
this
>> yeah yeah
>> a good a good run for the Panthers at
least on paper.
>> Yep. I would agree with that. Bri, uh
what team and what move stood out to
you? For mine was a little bit on the
offensive side of the ball. The Saints
boosting the arsenal with running back
Travis ETN. Who?
>> Travis who?
>> Yeah. Well, made a video and said that
he wants to go back to being called
Achan now. Um and the only reason he
went away from that was that people
never pronounced it correctly.
>> So now he said, "Yes, Achan." Now
whether New Orleans didn't think that
Jeremiah Love would be available at that
eight spot and would rather go wide
receiver to pair with Crystal L or they
just wanted to go more of the veteran
route with Han. But he's a guy that
great cut timing, patient letting blocks
develop, can generate yards after catch.
Um and I think he's going to be really
productive and just another guy for them
to be able to use.
>> Yep.
>> As as Alvin Camar's great career winds
down, now they got another guy.
>> Oh, not we're got to get downhill. Um
like not I don't think any Bucks fans
are too sad about that career winding
down. He did plenty of damage for sure.
But um all right, that's going to do it
for us on this kind of roundup of what
the NFC South did in free agency as
well. And I'm sure there's going to be
even more news as we now are going into
fullblown draft mode. So make sure
you're staying tuned to everything here
on Bucks Insider and Road to the Draft
when it comes to all of our upcoming
draft coverage. And we'll see you next
time.